# MICHAEL KHA

Software engineer adept at abstract and low-level concepts from an architect's approach. Capable of researching and applying unfamiliar technologies by comparing use cases, alternatives, and trade-offs. Proficient with scaling and automated deployment of systems. Pursuing positions relevant to full-stack, cloud, and data infrastructure.

# **EDUCATION**

B.Sc. in Software Engineering | Cooperative Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

Minors: Mathematics, Computer Science | GPA: 3.7

08/2017 - 05/2021

Courses: Analysis of Algorithms, System Requirements and Architecture, Cloud Computing, Data Management, Data Mining, Computer Vision, Statistics, Linear Algebra, Graph Theory, Combinatorics

# SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, C/C++, JavaScript

Cloud Providers: AWS, GCP, Azure

Technologies: Git, React (Hooks/Redux), OpenCV

DevOps: Vagrant, CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible,

Data: SQL, NoSQL, Kafka, Spark, Cassandra, Hadoop

Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Server Architecture

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Al Software Engineer Intern | IOMAXIS - Remote

05/2020 - 08/2020

- Introduced MLOps to automate workflows and shift research business model to development on AI R&D team
- Researched automated AI workflow platforms (such as Airflow) used by tech companies in production systems
- Proposed distributed ETL pipeline to centralize data, while automating data extraction and pre-processing
- · Led automated deployment of service using Vagrant, agnostic to AWS or on-premise environment for migrations
- · Leveraged Docker and Kubernetes for configuration, resource management, and scaling of Kafka
- Kafka, Spark, Cassandra, AWS, Vagrant, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Jira, Scrum

#### Cloud Software Developer Intern | IOMAXIS - Arlington, VA

01/2020 - 05/2020

- · Refined hybrid cloud security concept to a functional product, automating builds using major cloud services
- Created Flask API endpoints with OAuth2.0 bearer authentication to secure user access to build details
- Validated and optimized cloud service requests by leveraging multiprocessing to improved reliability of builds
- Verified builds successfully deployed with Bamboo CI to monitor logs and test network connectivity
- Python, Flask, JavaScript, React, SQLite, AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker, Ansible, Bamboo, Jira, Scrum

## Software Engineer Intern | Norfolk Southern - Atlanta, GA

05/2019 - 08/2019

- Implemented changes to database API, recording status of 180,000 monthly cars at terminals and on the line
- · Identified the value of disaster recovery for mission-critical systems and domain knowledge in business
- · Java, Python, C, Perl, Db2 SQL, Jenkins

#### Teaching Assistant | Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

08/2019 - Present

- · Supporting cloud course with topics in architecture, containerization, automated deployment, and big data
- Previously assisted system design course that introduces design patterns, APIs, metric analysis, and refactoring

### **PROJECTS**

Senior Capstone Project | % addletic.com – League Management and Social Platform

08/2020 - Present

- Development of sports league management full-stack application with the customer as the product owner
- Rearchitecting system by analyzing incomplete features, reducing code debt, and applying best practices
- Overhauling client-side state management and AWS server deployment to deliver functional product
- Python, Django, TypeScript, React, Redux, Sass, Postgres, AWS, CloudFormation, Docker, Jira, Scrum

## **Cloud Microservice Simulation** | O burger-order-microservice

09/2019 - 12/2019

- Proof of concept demonstrating microservice orchestration using SQS by tracking a defined process or pipeline
- Auto-scaling of services triggered based on SQS request traffic using custom CloudWatch metrics
- · Ruby on Rails, React-Rails, AWS, DynamoDB, Docker